This episode, I should shoot outdoors,
but there is too much brothel outside,
with wind, planes and lawn mowers.
So, we are indoors.
All living things, and it's obvious, do not breathe in the same way.
A fish underwater cannot breath. Like a bird in the sky.
In any case, the logic of this process is similar.
Whether you have lungs, or grills in the case of a fish,
or also the leaves in plants,
breathing, consists in bringing oxygen into the body's cells,
to produce energy.
This is not a big surprise, but we are gonna focus on the human body.
Although we can still note that for the insects the system is much simpler.
This is not surprising if we are interested on insects in robotics,
it's because these are organisms that are, easy to understand.
Insects have no lungs, grills, or leaves.
Insects, in fact, have open pipes that go through their body.
Internal airstreams, if you want,
and in fact, when the air go through these pipes, it is in direct contact with the cells,
and therefore the oxygen is brought directly to the cell.