We have fooled the aliens.
It was unintended, but we sent them
a completely wrong message about who we are.
Think about this,
How would you explain to these intelligent beings from other galaxies
what the human race is.
Does it look like this.
This is the drawing we sent them in 1972
in the Pioneer 10 space probe.
It's estimated it will reach its destination in millions of years.
In the meantime, if an alien happens to find it,
it can infer that in our planet there are two types of beings,
those who do things
and those who don't do anything.
My question is, Why did we decide to send this drawing.
and not this one, for example.
or this one.
Or even this one.
If we intended to represent human life on Earth,
none of these two drawings should have Caucasian traits,
as there are more people with African or Asian traits
in our planet.
However, we decided to send the one with the white man raising his hand
and the woman next to him.
Today, these two figures are spinning around the universe
and we don't know what will happen to them.
Something similar happens
with the images sent by the media,
images they cast off, adrift,
without really considering if they represent us
or if they have any affect
in how we would be in a million years.